bloglovin.com 2015-06-29

# Bloglovin

## 1\. Introduction

Bloglovin Group (“we“, “us”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (together with our Terms of Use and any other documents referred to in it) applies to www.bloglovin.com, Bloglovin mobile application(s), and Bloglovin widgets available via third party sites (the “Service”) and sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be handled by us. In this Privacy Policy, the term "personal data" means information that relates to an identified or identifiable natural person. 

We know that you, the user of the Service, are concerned about how we use and disclose personal data. We are dedicated to openness regarding the ways in which we use and disclose personal data, and we are committed to complying with data protection and privacy laws that apply to us. Importantly, we want to give you control over personal data that we process about you when you use the Service. 

We wish to remind you that this Privacy Policy applies to personal data that we process when you use the Service. It does not apply to any links to third parties' websites and/or services that you may encounter when you use the Service (including, without limitation, any blogs which you may access when you the Service and any user feedback services that the Service may provide links to). We encourage you to carefully familiarize yourself with privacy policies applicable to any websites and/or services operated by third parties. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third parties, such as the UserVoice-provided “Contact Support” functionality accessible through the Service. 

Please be aware that other users of the Service may be able to see certain personal data you have submitted to the Service. Therefore, please be careful when sharing personal data about you generally in the Service and with other users of the Service. If you register with the Service, you will create a publicly visible user profile under your username. The profile allows other users of the Service to see for instance your name, location, your picture/avatar and profile text (if such data is provided to us by you), blogs and users you follow in the Service and users that are following you, and the posts and other items that you “like” in the Service. Such data may be shown on your profile page, in connection with the posts you like in the Service, on the profile page for the blogs you follow and in social features of the Service. If you wish, you may flag blogs you are following as "private" on the “Manage the blogs you follow” page in the Service, in which case your profile information is removed from the blog profile and the blog is removed from your user profile. However, other items specified above will still be visible for other users of the Service. 

The social features of the Service also allow you to follow other users and other users to follow you. Your profile will be visible on the profile page of the users who follow you, and the users following you will be able to see when you start following other users. You can also connect your user profile with a blog, if you prove that you own that blog. In this case the blogs you own and blog profile texts for such blogs, if any, will be visible to other users in connection with your profile and in blog listings. You can manage the settings relating to your own blog on the “My blog” page in the Service. 

BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU ACCEPT THE PRIVACY PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. 

## 2\. The Data We Collect

In this Section 2 we describe the personal data we collect.

### (i) Personal data you provide to the Service

We may collect the following information from our users that may, in certain circumstances, alone or in connection with other data, constitute personal data: 

  * Full name 
  * Username 
  * E-mail address 
  * Password 
  * Location 
  * Blogs that you follow in the Service 
  * User picture or avatar (provided that you give this information) 
  * User profile text (provided that you give this information) 
  * Blogs owned by you and the related blog profile text (provided that you give this information) 
  * Information on your interactions with other users of the Service, such as information on which users you follow in the Service 
  * Information on your use of the Service, such as information regarding the posts that you “like” in the Service 

If you use a third party service, such as Facebook Connect, for signing into the Service, we may collect personal data, such as your user ID, name, e-mail address, profile picture/avatar that are available in your public profile with the third party service you use for signing into the Service. We may also share the information that you “liked” an item or started following a blog on your Facebook timeline; if you do not wish us to share this information, you may inactivate it on your Settings page in the Service. The Service also includes a “Find friends from Facebook” feature which enables you to find other users of the Service that you have as Facebook friends. 

### (ii) Data Collected Automatically

When you use the Service, we automatically collect data that may in certain circumstances constitute personal data:

  * We may place a "cookie" on the hard drive of the device that you use to access the Service. Cookies are text files that are saved on the hard drive of your device by means of your browser, enabling us to recognize your browser for purposes such as automatically authenticating you and logging you in to the Service, saving your preferences and directing relevant content to you. Most of the currently available browsers give you the option of managing cookies by, for example, disabling them entirely, accepting them individually, and deleting saved cookies from your hard drive. We would like to remind you that if you completely disable cookies on your browser, you might not be able to use some features of the Service. 
  * We may also place tracking pixels in the Service. A tracking pixel is a transparent graphic image that is placed on a web page and, in combination with a cookie, allows for the collection of information regarding the use of the web page that contains the tracking pixel. 
  * We use API keys of third-party software to authenticate the user to us. 
  * Google Analytics is an element of the Service. By using cookies, Google Analytics collects and stores data such as time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page of the website, the Internet Protocol address, and the type of operating system used in the devices used to access the Service. By using a browser plugin http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/plugin/ provided by Google, you can opt out of Google Analytics. 
  * We also use the analytics software service providers to provide us with statistical information related to your use of the Service, including, but not limited to, Mixpanel, Quantcast and comScore. 

### (iii) Data Collected Through Our Widgets

Our data collection devices include widgets, which run on third party sites to enable visitors of third party blogs to follow those blogs on Bloglovin. Bloglovin widgets collect the same personal information that may be collected by other aspects of the Service, as described above. In addition, if you use a third party site that has installed a Bloglovin widget, we may collect certain metadata about you such as (i) unique identifiers, (ii) the geo-location, (iii) whether you are currently logged into Bloglovin.com, and (iv) the url of the blog where the widget is located. We also track the page load where the widget is located and any clicks on the widget. We may also correlate your use of such third party sites with your Bloglovin profile. 

## 3\. The Purposes for Which We Use the Data

We use the data we collect for the following purposes: 

**a) Personal data you provide to the Service:** We may use the personal data you provide to the Service for the following purposes: 

  * To set up and maintain your registration with the Service; 
  * To communicate with you, including sending you an optional digest of new blog posts. You can manage your preferences regarding the digests on the “Settings” page of the Service; 
  * To provide features available in the Service; 
  * To develop, improve, and protect the Service; 
  * For direct marketing and market research, including for example reading recommendations and targeted marketing, in accordance with applicable law; 
  * To prevent and investigate fraud and other misuses; and 
  * To protect our rights and/or our property. 

**b) Data collected automatically:** We may use the data collected automatically for the following purposes:

  * To manage the Service; 
  * To provide features available in the Service; 
  * To personalize the Service. In particular, cookies may be used for providing us information on the blogs that you looked at before registering to the Service. We use this information to provide you with blog recommendations; 
  * To develop, improve, and protect the Service; 
  * For market research and data analysis, including for example reading recommendations and behavioral targeting and targeted marketing, in accordance with applicable law; 
  * To audit and analyze the Service; and 
  * To ensure the technical functionality and security of the Service. 

## 4\. How We Disclose Data

The data collected in the Service may be disclosed in the following manner: 

**a) Personal data you provide to the Service:** We may disclose personal data you provide to the Service with the following categories of third parties: 

  * To other users of the Service in accordance with this Privacy Policy; 
  * To our advertising partners in compliance with applicable laws; 
  * To service providers, such as email communications providers, customer support tools and feedback service providers; 
  * To public authorities, such as law enforcement, if we are legally required to so or if we need to protect our rights or the rights of third parties; and 
  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates; or a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Service and their advisors in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, or the sale of substantially all of our stock and/or assets or other corporate reorganization, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

**b) Data collected automatically:** The data collected automatically in the Service may be disclosed to the following categories of third parties: 

  * To service providers, such as data analysis companies; 
  * To our advertising partners in compliance with applicable laws; 
  * To public authorities, such as law enforcement, if we are legally required to do so or if we need to protect our rights or the rights of third parties; and 
  * To our subsidiaries and affiliates; or a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Service and their advisors in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, or the sale of substantially all of our stock and/or assets or other corporate reorganization, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Moreover, we may disclose information to third parties in an aggregate format that does not constitute personal data and does not allow the identification of individual users. 

## 5\. Your Rights

You have the following rights with respect to the personal data we hold about you: 

  * **The right to know what data we hold about you:** If you have registered with the Service, the easiest way to review the personal data you have provided to the Service is to access your profile and account settings on the “Settings” page of the Service. On your settings page you can also make changes to the personal data we hold about you. If you have additional questions regarding the personal data we hold about you, please contact us at privacy@bloglovin.com. We seek to swiftly respond to your inquiry. We may charge a small processing fee if less than twelve (12) months has passed since your last inquiry relating to personal data we hold about you. 
  * **The right to have incomplete, incorrect, outdated, or unnecessary personal data corrected, deleted, or updated.** The easiest way to correct, delete, or update the personal data you have provided to the Service is to access your profile settings and enter the necessary changes there. If you have additional questions regarding the correction, deletion, or updating of the personal data we hold about you, please contact us at privacy@bloglovin.com. 
  * **The right to opt out of receiving electronic direct marketing communications from us:** All electronic direct marketing communications that you may receive from us, such as e-mail messages, give you an option of not receiving such communications from us in the future. If you have any additional questions about electronic direct marketing received from us, please contact us atprivacy@bloglovin.com. 

## 6\. Data Security

The security of personal data is important to us. For example, your user account is protected by a password, the servers we use are secured and protected by a firewall, and we restrict access to personal data to employees, contractors and agents who need to know such personal data in order to operate, develop or improve the Service. 

Even so, we cannot guarantee that your personal data are always secure because data security measures in use from time to time may be vulnerable. Consequently, please be mindful of the risks that personal data about you may be exposed to when you use the Service. 

## 7\. International Transfers of Personal Data

If you are located in the European Union, please note that some of the servers where the Service is hosted may be located in countries outside the European Union. The laws applicable to the protection of personal data in such countries may be different from your home country. By registering with the Service, you consent to personal data about you being transferred outside the European Union. 

Moreover, if you are located outside the European Union, please note that some of your data may be located on servers within the European Union or Sweden. 

## 8\. Children’s Privacy

The Service is not intended for users younger than thirteen (13) years of age. We do not intend to collect any personal data from children under thirteen (13) years of age. 

## 9\. Changes to the Privacy Policy

From time to time we may change this Privacy Policy. You can tell when changes have been made to the Privacy Policy by referring to the "Last Updated" legend on top of this page. If we materially change the ways in which we use and disclose personal data, we will post a notice in the Service and send an e-mail to our registered users. Your continued use of the Service following any changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of any such changes made. 

## 10\. Questions or Concerns?

Should you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, your privacy as it relates to the use of the Service, or the protection of the personal data we hold about you, please contact us at privacy@bloglovin.com. We seek to swiftly resolve any concerns you may have.
